snapon.com 2005-04-01

# Privacy Policy

**Privacy Practices Statement**

**Snap-on Tools Company LLC Online Privacy Policy**

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

The privacy of your personally identifiable information is important to us. As part of our commitment to the privacy of your personally identifiable information that we collect online ("Personal Information"), we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your Personal Information is collected and used at this site. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where Personal Information is requested. This revised Privacy Policy is effective as of October 26, 2004.

The privacy practices set forth in this Privacy Policy are for this site only. Other Snap-on Tools Company LLC ("Snap-on") affiliate Web sites may have different practices. If you link to or otherwise visit any other Web sites, please review the privacy policies posted at those sites. Also, if you are an employee of Snap-on or its affiliate, please note that other internal company policies apply to you related to employee use of company computer systems and networks.

**Consent**

Please read this policy carefully. Your use of this Web site constitutes your consent to the information collection, use, and disclosure practices described below.

**Foreign Visitors**

The Site is directed to persons located in the United States only, and is not intended for use by persons located in other jurisdictions.

**Active Collection of Personal Information**

In general, when you visit our site you remain anonymous, but on some pages, you need to provide Personal Information to register, order products or services, contact Snap-on Tools Company LLC ("Snap-on"), and conduct other transactions via the Web site. The types of Personal Information actively collected at the Web site may include any or all of the following, depending on your activities on the Web site: 

Name, company, occupation, Snap-on customer number (if applicable), address, e-mail address, phone number, fax number, and credit/debit card/procurement card information, username, password, online training requested and received, personal financial details about dealer-applicants, and other Personal Information that you actively provide to us via the Web site.

We also enable you to submit personally identifiable information about other people. For example, we request that you provide us with such information about your dealer or representative or, if you order a gift online and want it sent directly to the recipient, you might submit the recipient's name and address. The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected about other people at these pages include: dealer or representative's name and contact information, and a gift recipient's name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number.

**Passive Information Collection**

The Web site may "passively" collect certain kinds of information during your visit, including but not limited to:

_Cookies_ : "Cookies" are small text files sent from a website to the hard drive of a user's computer to store bits of information related to that user. Cookies can store a variety of information, including IP addresses, navigational data, server information, data transfer times, user preferences, and passwords needed to access the special areas on the Site. We use cookies for the purpose of operating a shopper's ID to keep track of items in your shopping cart. We also use cookies to identify who you are after you log in or register. We also use cookies to create a more personalized experience on our Web site, for instance, by making you aware of what's new on our Web site since your last visit. You usually can configure your Internet browser to reject cookies. However, if you do so, you might not be able to access certain pages or use important functions on the Web site.

_Other Passive Web site Tracking_. This Web site also uses Internet Protocol (IP) addresses and log files to identify server problems, to improve site content, and compile aggregated statistics about Web site usage and clickstream data. We also use Web beacons to help personalize your experience, similarly to how we use cookies. Companies that help us place advertisements on our site use Web beacons to serve cookies and advertisements. We also use Web beacons to gather non-personally identifiable information about the number of users who visit our Web site, the areas which they spend their time visiting, and other demographic data. Only Snap-on and our advertising agency will have access to the data obtained with Web beacons.

**Snap-on also reserves the right to introduce new passive tracking technologies and techniques related to the use of the Web site. In general, we do not link your identity with information that we collect passively. However, in any situation where you log in with your username and password, any or all of the information that is passively collected about your activities on the Web site may be linked with your identity, and therefore may become Personal Information about you.**

**The Purposes for Which We Use and Disclose Personal Information**

We use and disclose Personal Information obtained when you place an order or access this Web site to process and complete that order, and to provide a more personalized shopping experience.

We maintain certain Personal Data related to financial payments, such as credit/debit card/procurement card information, only until payment for your order is processed, unless you authorize the information to be stored for future visits. If you later decide that you do not want us to store such information, you may contact us at [eorders@snapon.com](mailto:eorders@snapon.com) and ask us to delete such information.

We also use Personal Information to communicate with you, for example, to answer the e-mail and correspondence we receive, to confirm your order, to send more information about becoming a dealer, to send renewal notices, and to notify you of important changes in the functionality of the Web site or other notices related to the handling of your Personal Information. 

We may use Personal Information to make recommendations for additional products or special offers, and to provide you with updates on new products that we believe may be of interest to you, in situations where you expressly request such communications. If you have previously asked to receive this information, but do not want to receive this information in the future, please contact us at [eorders@snapon.com](mailto:eorders@snapon.com).

From time to time, we may share certain Personal Information with select third parties including other Snap-on affiliates and independent Snap-on dealers in your area to enable them to offer products or services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to share such Personal Information in the future, please contact us at [eorders@snapon.com](mailto:eorders@snapon.com) and we will take reasonable measures to avoid sharing such information in the future. Please note that such third parties are usually independent from Snap-on, and if you wish to stop all communications from such parties, you will need to address such issues with the third parties directly. 

We may disclose Personal Information in response to legal process or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, for example, in response to a court order, subpoena or a law enforcement agency's request. We also reserve the right to disclose Personal Information to protect the security of the Web site, to protect ourselves and our affiliated companies against liability, and/or in connection with any sale, assignment, or other transfer of all or a part of our business.

We may share Personal Information with our consultants or service providers to help us serve you better. We also contract other companies and individuals (collectively "Suppliers") to perform functions on our behalf, including without limitation, fulfilling and processing orders, processing credit card payments, handling shipping and returns, sending communications to you, and providing customer services. We require the Suppliers to agree to abide by Snap-on's privacy policy and only use your Personal Information, including certain Personal Data related to financial payments, such as credit/debit card/procurement card information, only until payment for your order is processed, and only to the extent necessary to perform their functions, and may not use it for any other purpose.

We will not use or share the Personal Information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without first providing you an opportunity to opt out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

**Customization and Aggregate data**

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our Web site and gather information for product management and development at Snap-on. For example, we may tell our sales and marketing staff that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our Web site, or that Y number of software licenses were ordered during a particular time period, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals. This aggregate information may also be shared with Snap-on's affiliates and independent dealers.

**Our Commitment to Data Security**

We maintain reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to protect Personal Information. When you place orders or access your account information, we usually offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software receives encrypted information through the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) of your internet browser which encrypts the Personal Information you input before it is sent to us and seeks to prevent anyone else from reading it as the information travels from your computer to ours. If you are still concerned about placing an order online, please feel free to call a customer service representative at 1-877-762-7664 and place your order via phone.

**Children's Privacy**

Snap-on has no intention of collecting personal information from children at this site.

**How You Can Access or Correct Your Information**

If you are a registered user of the Web site, you can access and correct certain Personal Data that we collect online and maintain by clicking on "Your Account" and entering your username and password. For other questions related to updating or changing your account information, please send an e-mail to [eorders@snapon.com](mailto:eorders@snapon.com). If any errors in your Personal Information cannot be corrected by accessing "Your Account", please contact us using the contact information below. You may also contact us using the information below to ask us to remove your Personal Information from our records, electronic or otherwise. However, we will need to maintain certain Personal Information about your product purchases in our records for purposes such as warranty and product information.

**Usernames and Passwords**

It is your responsibility to safeguard any username or password that you have received in connection with the Web site, and to notify us if you ever suspect that the security and confidentiality of such username or password has been compromised in any way. You are solely responsible for any use of this Web site via your username and password.

**Access**

If Personal Information you have submitted through the Web site is no longer accurate, current, or complete, and you wish to update it, please send an-mail to [eorders@snapon.com](mailto:eorders@snapon.com). We will usually be glad to update your information, but we reserve the right to use Personal Information obtained previously to verify your identity, to administer our warranty program, or to take other actions that we believe are appropriate.

**Collection of Personal Information by Third-Party Sites**

Sometimes we may offer promotions or specials that are sponsored by or co-sponsored with identified third parties. By virtue of their sponsorship, these third parties may obtain Personal Data that you submit to participate in the promotion or special. Snap-on has no control over the third-party sponsors' use of this information. We will notify you at the time of requesting Personal Information if third-party sponsors will obtain such information, and obtain your express consent for such disclosures.

**Changes to the Policy**

Our privacy practices, like the online medium itself, are subject to change. We reserve the right to change this policy from time to time in our sole discretion. Please check this policy frequently and particularly before you submit additional Personal Information via the Web site. All revisions to this Privacy Policy will be posted on the site via a link from the home page of the site. In the event that we change a significant or material term in this Privacy Policy, we will notify affected visitors by revising the link on the home page to read **"Newly Revised Privacy Policy"** that notifies visitors of the change.

**How to Contact Us**  
Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please send an email to [eorders@snapon.com](mailto:eorders@snapon.com) or mail correspondence to Snap-on Tools Company LLC, 2801 80th Street, P.O. Box 1410, Kenosha, WI 53141-1410.  
  
. .
